Guide to the Architect & Engineer File circa 1790-1989 PR 3
New-York Historical Society
- Unidentified Creators (80 projects), 15377; Various groups of drawings by unknown artists, architects and engineers are grouped according to common attributes such as project name. Unidentified Architect, Artist, or Engineers are located in PR 3-27, 91, 93-96, 99, 103, 105-108, 110, 112, 115, 117, 118, 120-124, 126-131, 133-135, 137, 138, 140, 143, 145-170, 175, 176, 181, 186-190, 192, 197, 199-201, 203, 211, 220, 227, 231.
  These files include drawings made by unidentified architects, engineers, etc. The following is a partial inventory, which is still in process.
  - Hamilton Grange, 10 items (PR 3-27), 1933; 203972 (Box PR 3-27)
  - [Unidentified 2 story estate house with cupola], 1 item (PR 3-91), 203975 (Box PR 3-91)
  - [Plans for J. Wm.Beekman] (PR 3-93), 1899; 205016 (Folder PR 3-93)
  - [Unidentified building] Main Office (PR 3-94) (Folder PR 3-94)
  - [Unidentified Machinery Part] (PR 3-95) (Folder PR 3-95)
  - West Street Proposal for Improvement (PR 3-99) (Folder PR 3-99)
  - New York City Depressed Railway, perspective view (PR 3-103) (Folder PR 3-103)
  - Wyckoff House, Brooklyn, NY (PR 3-105) (Folder PR 3-105)
    a measure drawing of the Pieter Claesen Wyckoff residence.
  - English Patent No. 11625 (PR 3-106) (Folder PR 3-106)
  - Audience Chamber (PR 3-107) (Folder PR 3-107)
  - Weight Distribution Specifications of Railroad Cars (PR 3-110) (Folder PR 3-110)
  - Windows on Fifth Avenue front (PR 3-112) (Folder PR 3-112)
  - Sketch of Lot at Greenwich and Cortlandt Streets, plus plans for a four story building. (PR 3-113) (Folder PR 3-113)
  - Landscape Design Plan (PR 3-114) (Folder PR 3-114)
  - Unidentified Building, Front Elevation (PR 3-115) (Folder PR 3-115)
  - Three Frame Designs with floral motifs (PR 3-117) (Folder PR 3-117)
  - Elevations for a Two Story House (PR 3-118) (Folder PR 3-118)
  - Waste Weir (PR 3-120) (Folder PR 3-120)
  - Farm Bridges (PR 3-121) (Folder PR 3-121)
  - Bridge at New London (PR 3-122) (Folder PR 3-122)
  - Gates for Lock No. 1 (PR 3-123) (Folder PR 3-123)
  - Schoharie Creek Bridge (PR 3-124) (Folder PR 3-124)
  - Trestle Bridge at O. Sherman's (PR 3-126) (Folder PR 3-126)
  - Dam across the Mohawk, at Rome (PR 3-127), 1851 (Folder PR 3-127)
  - Deck Bridge over the Mohawk River (PR 3-128) (Folder PR 3-128)
  - Unidentified Bridge/Dam, Plan of Bulkhead and Feeder (PR 3-129), 1854 (Folder PR 3-129)
  - Bridge over Erie Canal at Rome (PR 3-130) (Folder PR 3-130)
  - Unidentified Bridge, Plan of Docking (PR 3-131) (Folder PR 3-131)
  - Unidentified Trestle Bridge (PR 3-133) (Folder PR 3-133)
  - Unidentified Railroad Bridge (PR 3-134) (Folder PR 3-134)
  - Unidentified Culvert Drawings (PR 3-135) (Folder PR 3-135)
  - Unidentified Tramway Drawings (PR 3-137), 1878 (Folder PR 3-137)
  - Elevation of a Dredge (PR 3-138) (Folder PR 3-138)
  - House on Madison Avenue between 39th and 40th Streets (PR 3-140) (Folder PR 3-140)
  - New York Post Office (PR 3-143) (Folder PR 3-143)
  - St. John's Chapel (PR 3-145), 1933 (Folder PR 3-145)
  - Woolworth House, Elevations and Floor Plans (PR 3-146) (Folder PR 3-146)
  - Bell House, Perspective Views (PR 3-147) (Folder PR 3-147)
  - Building on Corner of Madison Avenue and 82nd Street, Floor Plans (PR 3-148), 1930 (Folder PR 3-148)
  - 49 East 76th Street, Elevations and Floor Plans (PR 3-149) (Folder PR 3-149)
  - Hunter House (PR 3-150) (Folder PR 3-150)
  - F. Kurtz Building, 90th Street and Fifth Avenue (PR 3-151) (Folder PR 3-151)
  - Springler Institute, Front Elevation (PR 3-152) (Folder PR 3-152)
  - Park Building (PR 3-153) (Folder PR 3-153)
  - House for Dr. Robinson, Flue Section of Walls Nos. 1-6 (PR 3-154) (Folder PR 3-154)
  - House for John Rogers, Esq., Elevations and Floor Plans (PR 3-155) (Folder PR 3-155)
  - House on Grand Street, Elevations and Floor Plans (PR 3-156) (Folder PR 3-156)
  - Houses on 95th Street and 8th Avenue, Elevations and Sections (PR 3-157) (Folder PR 3-157)
  - Commercial Building on 24th Street, Elevations (PR 3-158) (Folder PR 3-158)
  - Commercial Building at Broadway and 47th Street, Elevations (PR 3-159) (Folder PR 3-159)
  - Unidentified House, Elevations (PR 3-160) (Folder PR 3-160)
  - Commercial Building on Cedar Street (PR 3-161), 1867 (Folder PR 3-161)
  - Henry C. Sturges Residence, 56 West 34th Street, Proposed Alterations (PR 3-162) (Folder PR 3-162)
  - Unidentified House, Floor Plans, Elevations, and Perspective Views (PR 3-163) (Folder PR 3-163)
  - Unidentified House, Floor Plans and Elevations (PR 3-164) (Folder PR 3-164)
  - New York Sewers, Sections and Plans (PR 3-165), 1898-1899 (Folder PR 3-165)
  - Prints of Illustrations of Fortification Plans (PR 3-166) (Folder PR 3-166)
  - Marshall O. Roberts Estate, Floor Plans, Elevations and Sections (PR 3-167) (Folder PR 3-167)
  - Commercial Building at Broadway and Fifth Avenue, Elevations (PR 3-168) (Folder PR 3-168)
  - Unidentified Public Building [Possibly Hospital or Orphanage], Elevations (PR 3-169) (Folder PR 3-169)
  - Morris-Jumel Mansion, Floor Plans (PR 3-170) (Folder PR 3-170)
  - West Side Improvement, Plans for Highway at Riverside Drive (PR 3-175), 1925-1929 (Folder PR 3-175)
  - Harlem River Bridge and Aqueduct Drawings (PR 3-176) (Folder PR 3-176)
  - Church in Massachusetts, Plans (PR 3-181), 1859 (Folder PR 3-181)
  - Water Main Section Drawing (PR 3-186) (Folder PR 3-186)
  - Washington Square Reformed Dutch Church, Alterations to Basement (PR 3-187), 1866 (Folder PR 3-187)
  - Peter Hetzog Theological Hall, Floor Plans, (PR 3-188), 1876 (Folder PR 3-188)
  - Unidentified Floor Plan (PR 3-189) (Folder PR 3-189)
  - New York Tunnels and Aqueduct, Excavation Drawings (PR 3-190) (Folder PR 3-190)
  - Cour de Bergeries (PR 3-192) (Folder PR 3-192)
  - Various Unidentified Churches, Elevations, Sections, and Floor Plans (PR 3-197) (Folder PR 3-197)
  - Village of Larchmont Sewer Plans (PR 3-199), 1899 (Folder PR 3-199)
  - Unidentified Roof Framing Plans (PR 3-200) (Folder PR 3-200)
  - Unidentified Building, Elevation and Plan (PR 3-201) (Folder PR 3-201)
  - Abercrombie and Fitch, Floor Plans (PR 3-203) (Folder PR 3-203)
  - Plans for Piers on River Front, 151 Street to 158 Street (PR 3-211) (Folder PR 3-211)
  - Gracie Mansion, Front Elevation (PR 3-220) (Folder PR 3-220)
  - 25 Sutton Place, Floor Plans (PR 3-227) (Folder PR 3-227)
  - Bank Street Row House, Floor Plan (PR 3-229) (Folder PR 3-229)
  - President's Square, Connecting Building Between War and Navy Offices (PR 3-231) (Folder PR 3-231)